Guide to the William L. Brown, Jr. papers,1960-1990.
Brown, William L., Jr.
- Series VII. Manuscripts, Notes, Maps, Articles, Reprints, Correspondence, Studies and Data
  - Jurzykowski Property, Brazil, 1972-1973 (Box 12, Folder 40)
  - Kahl, Philip, Jr., 1952-1989 (Box 12, Folder 41)
  - Kannowski, Paul B., 1953-1974 (Box 12, Folder 42)
  - Kazaan, Peter, 1972 (Box 12, Folder 43)
  - Kempf, Walter, 1948-1962 (Box 12, Folder 44)
  - Kempf, Walter, 1963-1976 (Box 12, Folder 45)
  - Kim, Byung-Jin, 1982, 1987 (Box 12, Folder 46)
  - King, Ben, 1969-1971 (Box 12, Folder 47)
  - Kistner, David H., 1954-1975, 1983-1985 (Box 12, Folder 48)
  - Kondo, Yoshio, 1958-1961, 1976-1979 (Box 12, Folder 49)
  - Königsmann, Eberhard, 1963-1974, 1990 (Box 12, Folder 50)
  - Krombein, Karl V., 1949-1955, 1966-1979, 1987-1989 (Box 12, Folder 51)
  - Kubota, Masao, 1969-1984 (Box 12, Folder 52)
  - Kugler, Ronald Charles, 1972-1991 (Box 12, Folder 53)
  - Kusnezov, Nicolas, 1948-1966 (Box 12, Folder 54)
  - Kutter, Heinrich, 1952-1955, 1971-1979 (Box 12, Folder 55)
  - "L" (Miscellaneous Correspondence), 1955-1982 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Laffoon, Jean L., 1952 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Laham, Urless N., 1952-1956, 1977-1978 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Lattke, John E., 1977-1995 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Leech, Hugh B., 1951-1962 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Le Manse, G., 1952-1957, 1971-1976 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Lenko, Karol, 1962-1968 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Levi, Herbert, 1957-1962, 1970-1975 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Lévieux, Jean, 1964-1986 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Levin, Simon, 1972-1984 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Levings, Sally, 1976-1987 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Lieberburg, Ivan, 1971-1975 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Lindroth, Carl, 1958-1963, 1979 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Longino, Jack, 1981-1988, 1995 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Lowe, G. H., 1924, 1975-1976 (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Lowery, Bede B., 1957-1965, 1976-1978 (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - "Ma"-"Mc" (Miscellaneous Correspondence), 1958-1984 (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - "Me"-"My" (Miscellaneous Correspondence), 1954-1994 (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - Markl, Hubert, 1966-1973 (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - Maschwitz, Ulrich, 1966-1980 (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - Masuko, Keiichi, 1985-1994 (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - McAreavey, J. J., 1949-1957 (Box 13, Folder 22)
  - McCluskey, Elwood, 1960-1989 (Box 13, Folder 23)
  - McDonald, Michael, 1989-1994 (Box 13, Folder 24)
  - McEvoy, Miles, 1984-1988 (Box 13, Folder 25)
  - McGraw-Hill Book Company, 1968-1995 (Box 13, Folder 26)
  - McKittrick, Frances A., 1963-1966 (Box 13, Folder 27)
  - MCZ (Museum of Comparative Zoology), 1962-1974, 1992-1993 (Box 13, Folder 28)
  - Medler, John T., 1956-1959 (Box 13, Folder 29)
  - Meem, Jim, 1957-1961 (Box 13, Folder 30)
  - Mercovich, C., 1956-1958 (Box 13, Folder 31)
  - Messer, Adam, 1984 (Box 13, Folder 32)
  - Meyerriecks, Andrew J., 1959-1964, 1970-1979 (Box 13, Folder 33)
  - Michener, Charles D., 1955-1980 (Box 13, Folder 34)
  - Microcard Corporation, 1958-1962 (Box 13, Folder 35)
  - Miller, C. D. F. "Doug", 1953-1967 (Box 13, Folder 36)
  - Moffett, Mark W., 1979-1989 (Box 13, Folder 37)
  - Montagu, Ashley, 1963 (Box 13, Folder 38)
  - Moore, John A., 1953-1959, 1983 (Box 13, Folder 39)
  - Moss, W. Wayne, 1973-1978 (Box 13, Folder 40)
  - "N" and "O" (Miscellaneous Correspondence), 1957-1993 (Box 13, Folder 41)
  - National Science Foundation (NSF), 1957-1963, 1975, 1987 (Box 13, Folder 42)
  - Newton, Alfred F., 1977-1981 (Box 13, Folder 43)
  - New Zealand, Scientists from, 1952-1958 (Box 13, Folder 44)
  - Nixon, G. E. J., 1949-1968 (Box 13, Folder 45)
  - Odum, Howard T., 1965-1967 (Box 13, Folder 46)
  - Ogata, K., 1980-1987 (Box 13, Folder 47)
  - Onoyama, Keiichi, 1974, 1986-1988 (Box 13, Folder 48)
  - Orlove, Michael, 1966-1971, 1991 (Box 13, Folder 49)
  - OTS (Organization for Tropical Studies), 1965-1966, 1987 (Box 13, Folder 50)
  - Overal, William L., 1977-1982 (Box 13, Folder 51)
  - "P" (Miscellaneous Correspondence), 1949-1986 (Box 13, Folder 52)
  - Papp, Jenő, 1972-1983 (Box 13, Folder 53)
  - Park, Orlando, 1950-1963 (Box 13, Folder 54)
  - Parkes, Kenneth C., 1955-1958 (Box 13, Folder 55)
  - Pavan, M., 1955-1962 (Box 13, Folder 56)
  - Peck, Stewart B., 1969-1981 (Box 13, Folder 57)
  - Peeters, Christian P., 1982-1993 (Box 13, Folder 58)
  - Pimentel, David, 1963-1978 (Box 13, Folder 59)
  - Pisarski, B., 1961, 1970-1974, 1980 (Box 13, Folder 60)
  - Pitman, Rulon B., 1965-1967, 1977-1978 (Box 13, Folder 61)
  - Poinar, George O., Jr., 1963, 1975-1987 (Box 13, Folder 62)
  - de Polania, Ingeborg Zenner, 1975-1982 (Box 13, Folder 63)
  - Price, Peter W., 1969-1974 (Box 13, Folder 64)
  - "Q" and "R" (Miscellaneous Correspondence), 1949-1996 (Box 13, Folder 65)
  - Rabinovich, Jorge E., 1971-1973 (Box 13, Folder 66)
  - Ramberg, Frank B., 1980-1990 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Rawlins, John, 1978-1985 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Reichardt, Haus, 1966-1976 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Rehn, James A. G., 1944-1953 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Rettenmeyer, Carl, 1956-1980 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Riek, Edgar F., 1951-1968, 1974 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Ritter, Hope, 1961-1970 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Robertson, Hamish G., 1985-1994 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Robertson, Phyllis L., 1972-1985 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Root, Richard B., 1970-1976 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Ross, Edward S., 1948-1975, 1986 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Ross, Herbert H., 1949-1957, 1972 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Rotramel, George, 1964-1969 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - "Sa"-"Sh" (Miscellaneous Correspondence), 1949-1996 (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - "Si"-"Sw" (Miscellaneous Correspondence), 1947-1986 (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Sabrosky, Curtis W., 1954-1971 (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Salinas, Pedro José, 1982-1995 (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - Saunders, Chris J., 1961-1965 (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - Schmeider, Rudolf G. (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - Schneirla, T. C., 1953-1968, 1994 (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - Schultz, Theodore, 1988-1996 (Box 14, Folder 21)
  - Schwardt, H. H., 1957-1960 (Box 14, Folder 22)
  - Shattuck, Steven O., 1988-1994 (Box 14, Folder 23)
  - Short, Lester L., Jr., 1957-1968 (Box 14, Folder 24)
  - Simon, Jean Pierre, 1968-1975 (Box 14, Folder 25)
  - Slater, James A., 1954-1962, 1974 (Box 14, Folder 26)
  - Smith, David R., 1965-1983 (Box 14, Folder 27)
  - Smith, Edward H., 1964-1979 (Box 14, Folder 28)
  - Smith, Marion R., 1939-1951 (Box 14, Folder 29)
  - Smith, Marion R., 1952-1956 (Box 14, Folder 30)
  - Smith, Marion R., 1957-1966, 1979 (Box 14, Folder 31)
  - Snelling, Roy R., 1950, 1962-1990 (Box 14, Folder 32)
  - Soans, A. B. "Benny", 1963-1969, 1989 (Box 14, Folder 33)
  - Southwood, Richard, 1986-1987 (Box 14, Folder 34)
  - SSE (The Society for the Study of Evolution), 1968-1987 (Box 14, Folder 35)
  - SSE Business (The Society for the Study of Evolution), 1982-1984 (Box 14, Folder 36)
  - SSZ (The Society of Systematic Zoology), 1972-1974, 1984 (Box 14, Folder 37)
  - Stannard, Lew J., 1947-1965 (Box 14, Folder 38)
  - Starr, Christopher K., 1983-1989 (Box 14, Folder 39)
  - "T" (Miscellaneous Correspondence), 1951-1987 (Box 14, Folder 40)
  - Talbert, Larry, 1957 (Box 14, Folder 41)
  - Talbot, Mary, 1948-1969 (Box 14, Folder 42)
  - Taschenberg, E. F., 1965-1975 (Box 14, Folder 43)
  - Tauber, Maurice J., 1981-1985 (Box 14, Folder 44)
  - Taylor, Robert W., 1954-1966 (Box 14, Folder 45)
  - Taylor, Robert W., 1967-1973 (Box 14, Folder 46)
  - Taylor, Robert W., 1974-1977 (Box 14, Folder 47)
  - Taylor, Robert W., 1978-1996 (Box 14, Folder 48)
  - Terron, Georges, 1974-1975 (Box 14, Folder 49)
  - Tinault, A., 1989-1991 (Box 14, Folder 50)
  - Townes, Henry, 1957-1982 (Box 14, Folder 51)
  - Trager, James C., 1974-1988 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Travassos-Filho, Lauro P., 1976-1979 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Tremper, Brenda, 1973-1975 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Triplehorn, Charles A., 1957-1978 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Tulloch, George S., 1949-1963 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - "U" and "V" (Miscellaneous Correspondence), 1949-1993 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Umphrey, Gary, 1980-1996 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - United States Department of Agriculture, 1957-1961 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - United States Department of Agriculture (Plant Quarantine Division), 1965-1978 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Van Boven, J. K. A., 1950, 1973 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Van Pelt, Arnold, 1948-1970 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Van Halen, Leigh, 1967, 1977 (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Vanzolini, Paulo, 1951-1992 (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Vaurie, Charles, 1955-1958 (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Volpe, E. Peter, 1955 (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - "W" (Miscellaneous Correspondence), 1959-1995 (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - Walther, Joachim, 1983 (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - Wang, Min-Sheng, 1994 (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - Ward, Philip S., 1977-1995 (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - Waterhouse, Doug F., 1964-1976 (Box 15, Folder 20)
  - Weatherhill, Laurie H., 1961-1971 (Box 15, Folder 21)
  - Weber, Neal A., 1939-1987 (Box 15, Folder 22)
  - Werner, Floyd G., 1950-1980 (Box 15, Folder 23)
  - Wesson, Larry G., 1938-1949 (Box 15, Folder 24)
  - Weulersse, J. Casevitz, 1970-1994 (Box 15, Folder 25)
  - Wheeler, Diana E., 1982-1993 (Box 15, Folder 26)
  - Wheeler, George C., 1949-1989 (Box 15, Folder 27)
  - White, Jan, 1973-1975 (Box 15, Folder 28)
  - Willey, Robert B., 1956-1983 (Box 15, Folder 29)
  - Williams, Ernest E., 1969 (Box 15, Folder 30)
  - Willier, B. H., 1956-1957 (Box 15, Folder 31)
  - Wilson, Edward O., 1949-1961 (Box 15, Folder 32)
  - Wilson, Edward O., 1962-1984 (Box 15, Folder 33)
  - Wilson, Edward O., 1985-1996 (Box 15, Folder 34)
  - Wilson, John Wilbur, 1976-1978 (Box 15, Folder 35)
  - Wing, Merle W., 1967-1984 (Box 15, Folder 36)
  - Woodward, Tom, 1951-1972 (Box 15, Folder 37)
  - Wray, D. L., 1948-1963 (Box 15, Folder 38)
  - Wu, Jian, 1984-1988 (Box 15, Folder 39)
  - Wygodzinsky, Pedro, 1964-1979 (Box 15, Folder 40)
  - "X", "Y", and "Z" (Miscellaneous Correspondence), 1963-1991 (Box 15, Folder 41)
  - Yang, Man-Miao, 1988 (Box 15, Folder 42)
  - Yarrow, Ian H. H., 1952-1958 (Box 15, Folder 43)
  - Yasumatsu, Keizō, 1949-1972, 1983 (Box 15, Folder 44)
  - Zimmerman, Elwood C., 1957-1967 (Box 15, Folder 45)
  - (Lack of Information; Unsorted Correspondence) (Box 15, Folder 46)
  - Miscellaneous Research Notes and Reprints
  - Diacamma Genus Research Notes and Photographs, 1925, 1973, 1982-1991 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Myopias Genus Research Notes, (?), 1993-1994 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Pachycondyla Genus Photographs, c.1982 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Ponerini Photographs, 1982 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Simopelta Genus Research Notes, 1935, 1957-1971, 1989 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - "A Comprehensive Bibliography of Ant Systematics", c.1996 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - "Key to New World Pheidole species groups" and "A Comprehensive Bibliography of Ant Systematics", 1976, 1994, c.1996 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Kukalová-Peck, J. Reprints, 1969-1986 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Selander, Robert K. Reprints, 1962-1983 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Fossil Insect Papers, 1967-1994 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Miscellaneous Reprints (Box 16, Folder 11-22)
  - Miscellaneous Research Notes (Box 16, Folder 23)
- Series VIII. Administrative Records, Committee Reports
  - Annual Reports-Progress Reports-Project Descriptions-Revisions, 1962-1992 (Box 4, Folder 59)
  - Collection Committee, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 60)
  - College Advisory Committee, 1981-1987 (Box 4, Folder 61)
  - Entomology Department Accounts (Box 4, Folder 62)
  - Graduate Student Information, 1972-1989 (Box 4, Folder 63)
  - Graduate Student Minors (Box 4, Folder 64)
  - Report of the Entomology Library-Space Committee, October 27, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 65)
- Series IX. Trips
  - Africa Trip, 1962-1963 (Box 4, Folder 66)
  - Ants of 1969 Trip to Africa, Madagascar, India, Etc. (Box 4, Folder 67)
  - Africa-Madagascar-India Trip, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 68)
  - Ants of Amazon-Field Trip, 1962 (Box 4, Folder 69)
  - The Amazon Trip, 1962-1963 (Box 4, Folder 70)
  - NSF-Amazon Trip, 1962 (Box 4, Folder 71)
  - Ants from 1972 East Indies Trip (Box 4, Folder 72)
  - Australia-East Indies Trip, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 73)
  - Dominican Republic Trip-Summer, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 74)
  - NSF-European Trip, 1963-1964 (Box 4, Folder 75)
  - European Trip, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 76)
  - Mexican Trip, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 77)
  - New Guinea Trip, Etc. (Box 4, Folder 78)
  - South America Trip, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 79)
  - South America Trip-Correspondence, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 80)
  - Ants from 1981 Trip-New Guinea and SE Asia (Box 4, Folder 81)
  - South East Asia Trip-Correspondence, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 82)
- Series X. Karyotypes and Printing Materials
  - Contains: 1 Index Card Box and I Envelope of Karyotypes, 3 Envelopes of Etched Metal Plates, and 4 Wood Blocks (Box 5)
- Series XI. Notebooks
  - Contains: 3 Folders and 17 Notebooks (Box 6)
- Series XII. Oversize Galley Proofs (Box 7-9)
SEPARATED MATERIAL
Books in this collection have been sent to the Department of Entomology, National Museum of Natural History, Smithsonian Institution.
Formicina austriaca: Beschreibung der bisher im österreichischen Kaiserstaate aufgefundenen Ameisen, nebst hinzufügung jener in Deutschland, in der Schweiz und in Italien vorkommenden Arten - Mayr, Gustav L. - 1855
Mr. Smith's Catalogue of Hymenopterous Ants - Smith, Frederick - 1858
Descriptions of New Species of Hymenopterous Insects collected by Mr. A. R. Wallace at Celebes (p. 57); Descriptions of Hymenopterous Insects collected by Mr. A. R. Wallace in the Islands of Batchian, Kaisaa, Amboyna, Gilolo, and at Dory in New Guinea (p. 93) - Journal of the Proceedings of the Linnean Society: Supplemental to Vol. V-Zoology - Smith, Frederick; ("Communicated by") W. W. Saunders - 1860
Die Europäischen Formiciden Nach der analytischen Methode - Mayr, Gustav L. - 1861
Verzeichnifs der Formiciden-Gattungen und Arten - Berliner entomologische Zeitschift (Beilage) (7:165) - Roger, Julius - 1863
Formicidae - Novara-Expedition. Zoologischer Theil. Bd. II - Mayr, Gustav L. - 1865
Les Fourmis de la Suisse: Systématique, Notices Anatomiques et Physiologiques, Architecture, Distribution Géographique, Nouvelles Expérences et Observations de Mœurs - Neue Denkschriften der Allgemeinen Schweizerischen Gesellschaft für die Gesammten Naturwissenschaften: Nouveaux Mémoires de la Société Helvétique des Sciences Naturelles (Band XXVI. mit II Tafeln) - Forel, Auguste - 1874
Les Fourmis - Bibliothèque des Merveilles - André, Ernest - 1885
Histoire Naturelle des Hyménoptéres - Histoire Physique, Naturelle et Politique de Madagascar (Volume XX) - Forel, Auguste - 1891
Formicidae (Heterogyna) - Catalogus Hymenopterorum hucusque descriptorum systematicus et synonymicus (Vol. VII) - Dalla Torre, C. G. de - 1893
The Fauna of British India, Including Ceylon and Burma: Hymenoptera.-Vol. II. Ants and Cuckoo-Wasps - Bingham, C. T. - 1903
Beiträge zur Monographie der Formiciden des paläarktischen Faunengebietes - Deutsche Entomologische Zeitschrift (Heft II) - Emery, C. - 1908
Die psychischen Fähigkeiten der Ameisen: Mit einem Ausblick auf die vergleichende Tierpsychologie - Wasmann, Erich - 1909
Hymenoptera Fam. Formicidæ Subfam. Dorylinæ - Genera Insectorum (Fasc. 102) - Emery, C. - 1910
Hymenoptera Fam. Formicidæ Subfam. Ponerinæ - Genera Insectorum (Fasc. 118) - Emery, C. - 1911
Hymenoptera Fam. Formicidæ Subfam. Dolichoderinæ - Genera Insectorum (Fasc. 137) - Emery, C. - 1912
Die Insekten Mitteleuropas insebsondere Deutschlands (Band II: Hymenopteren) - Stitz, H. ("Die Armisen (Formicidae)"); Schmiedeknecht, O. ("Die Schlupf- und Brackwespen") - 1914
The Ants of the Baltic Amber - Sonderabdruck aus den Schriften der Physikalisch-ökonomischen Gesellschaft zu Königsberg i. Pr., LV. - Wheeler, William Morton - 1914
A Monograph of the Formicidae of South Africa - Annals of the South African Museum (Vol. XIV) - Arnold, George - 1915
Hymenoptera Formicidae: Die Ameisen der Schweiz - Fauna Insectorum Helvetiae - Forel, Auguste - 1915
Results of Dr. E. Mjöbergs Swedish Scientific Expeditions to Australia 1910-1913: 2. Ameisen - Arkiv für Zoologi utgifvet af K. Svenska Vetenskapsakademien (Band 9 / N:o 16) - Forel, Auguste - 1915
Fauna Entomologica Italiana: 1. Hymemoptera.-Formicidae - Estratto dal Bullettino della Societa Entomologica Italiana (XLVII-1916) - Emery, Carlo - 1916
Die Ameise Schilderung ihrer Lebenweise - Escherich, K. - 1917
Les Fourmis de France et de Belgique - Extrait des Annales de la Société Entomologique de France (Vol. LXXXVII) - Bondroit, J. - 1918
Die Gastpflege der Ameisen ihre biologischen und philosophischen Probleme - Abhandlungen zue theoretischen Biologie - Wasmann, Erich - 1920
Les Fourmis de la Suisse: Systématique, Notices Anatomiques et Physiologiques, Architecture, Distribution Géographique, Nouvelles Expérences et Observations de Mœurs (Seconde Édition Revue et Corrigée) - Nouveaux Mémoires de la Société Helvétique des Sciences Naturelles - Forel, Auguste - 1920
Ants of the American Museum Congo Expedition: A Contribution to the Myrmecology of Africa - Bulletin of the American Museum of Natural History (Vol. XLV) - Wheeler, William Morton - 1922
Keys to the Genera and Subgenera of Ants - Bulletin of the American Museum of Natural History (Vol. XLV, pp. 631-710) (Extracted from 'Ants of the American Congo Expedition. A Contribution to the Myrmecology of Africa.') - Wheeler, William Morton - 1922
Le Formiche della Venezia Giulia e della Dalmazia - Müller, Giuseppe - 1923
Hymenoptera Fam. Formicidæ Subfam. Formicinæ - Genera Insectorum (Fasc. 183) - Emery, C. - 1925
The New World Species of the Genus Solenopsis (Hymenop. Formicidae) - Proceedings of the American Academy of Arts and Sciences (Vol. 66, No. 2) - Creighton, William S. - 1930
On the Identity of Smith's Types of Formicidae (Hymenoptera) collected by Alfred Russell Wallace in the Malay Archipelago, with Descriptions of Two new Species - (From the) Annals and Magazine of Natural History, Ser. 10, Vol. X. p. 441 - Donisthorpe, Horace - 1932
Colony-Founding Among Ants, with an Account of Some Primitive Australian Species - Wheeler, William Morton - 1933
Studies of Neotropical Ant-Plants and Their Ants - Bulletin of the Museum of Comparative Zoölogy at Harvard College (Vol. XC, No. 1) - Wheeler, William Morton - 1942
A List of the Type-Species of the Genera and Subgenera of the Formicidae - (From the) Annals and Magazine of Natural History, Ser. 11, Vol. X. p. 617 - Donisthorpe, Horace - 1943
Check List of the Ants (Hymenoptera: Formicidae) of Asia - Monographs of the Institute of Science and Technology (Monograph 1) - Chapman, James W.; Santiago R. Capco - 1951
Catálago abreviado das Formigas da Região Neotropical (Hym. Formicidae) - Studia Entomologica (Vol. 15, Fasc. 1-4) - Kempf, Walter W. - 1972
Les Fourmis et Leur Milieu en France Méditerranéenne - Encyclopédie Entomologique (XLV) - Bernard, Francis - 1983
New Species of the Ant Genus Myopias (Hymenoptera: Formicidae: Ponerinae) - (Reprinted from) PSYCHE, Vol. 90, No. 3 - Willey, Robert B.; William L. Brown, Jr. - 1983
Hymenoptera Fam. Formicidæ Subfam. Myrmicinæ - Genera Insectorum (Fasc. 174) - Emery, C. - 1921 (?) ("1922")
The Formicidae of Australia (Vol. 1: Subfamily Myrmeciinae) - Clark, John - 1952 (?) ("Bolton cat. Gives 31-XII-1951")
Catalogo delle Specie di Formicidae d'Italia - Memorie della Società Entomologica Italiana (Volume 50) - Urbani, Cesare Baroni - 1971 ("issued 1973")